Guide to the James Weldon Johnson and Grace Nail Johnson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize and Other Storage, 87.83; (38 boxes)
  - Oversize
    - Receipts, brochures, and pamphlets from JWJ's trip to Japan (in Series V, Personal Papers), 1929 (Box 140, Folder 1155)
    - Commemorative stamp for JWJ and related ephemera (in Series V, Personal Papers), 1988 (Box 140, Folder 1156)
    - "The Subway Sun" broadside with JWJ quote (in Series V, Personal Papers), undated (Box 140, Folder 1157)
    - Plaque with resolution by City of Los Angeles recognizing Jim Mapp and the Playward Bus Theatre Company for its production of God's Trombones (in Series V, Personal Papers), 1981 (Box 140, Folder 1158)
    - Certificates to John E. Nail from the Selective Service System, City of New York George Washington Bi-centennial Commission, and Real Estate Board of New York; Certificate recognizing John B. Nail's membership in the Association for the Study of Negro Life and History; Certificate appointing Grayce F. Nail lieutenant of the New York Branch of the N.A.A.C.P. (in Series VIII, Family Papers), 1932-1943 (Box 141, Folder 1159)
    - Preparatory Diploma from Philander Smith College (Little Rock, Arkansas) (in Series VIII, Family Papers), 1927 (Box 141, Folder 1160)
    - Certificates (in Series VIII, Family Papers), 1934-1942 (Box 141, Folder 1161)
    - Allen, James (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1920-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1162)
    - Battey (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1904 (Box 142, Folder 1163)
    - Blackstone Photographic Service (in Series IX, Photographs), undated (Box 142, Folder 1164)
    - Patton Studio (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1920-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1165)
    - Pinchot, Ben (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1920-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1166)
    - Ulmann, Doris (in Series IX, Photographs), 1929 (Box 142, Folder 1167-1170)
    - Unidentified (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1874, 1920-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1171)
    - Bachrach (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1900 (Box 142, Folder 1172)
    - Marceau (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1900 (Box 142, Folder 1173)
    - "Atlanta University Quartette" (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1893 (Box 143, Folder 1174)
    - James Weldon Johnson with Bob Cole and Rosamond Johnson (in Series IX, Photographs), 1904 (Box 143, Folder 1175-1177)
    - "Honorary pallbearers at Bert Williams' funeral" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1922 (Box 143, Folder 1178)
    - James Weldon Johnson with Fisk University students and faculty (in Series IX, Photographs), 1931-1933 (Box 143, Folder 1179)
    - Meharry Medical College Graduating Classes (in Series IX, Photographs), 1937 (Box 143, Folder 1180)
    - "Dinner given by the American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers in honor of its President and Counsel Mr. George Maxwell and Mr. Nathan Burkan" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1914 November 29 (Box 144, Folder 1181)
    - "Citizens Club Banquet" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1915 January 23 (Box 144, Folder 1182)
    - "Beefsteak Dinner by the United Song Writers of America at Keens Chop House" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1916 March 29 (Box 144, Folder 1183)
    - "League of Small and Subject Nationalities" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1917 October 30 (Box 144, Folder 1184)
    - "Meeting and Dinner of the Conference on Demobilization and the Responsibilities of Organized Social Agencies" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1918 November 30 (Box 144, Folder 1185)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations (Kyoto, Japan) (in Series IX, Photographs), 1929 (Box 144, Folder 1186)
    - Dinner in Honor of JWJ (in Series IX, Photographs), 1931 May 14 (Box 144, Folder 1187)
    - "International House Day Banquet" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1937 November 19 (Box 144, Folder 1188)
    - "Twenty-fifth Annual Dinner American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1940 April 24 (Box 144, Folder 1189)
    - "Annual Dinner Meeting Song Writers' Protective Association" (in Series IX, Photographs), 1946 March 29 (Box 144, Folder 1190)
    - Larsen, Nella (in Series IX, Photographs), 1930 (Box 144, Folder 1191)
    - Van Vechten, Carl (in Series IX, Photographs), 1934 (Box 144, Folder 1192)
    - Johnson, J. Rosamond (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1873-1954 (Box 145, Folder 1193)
    - Braxton, Horace (in Series IX, Photographs), undated (Box 145, Folder 1194)
    - Nail, Frances Elizabeth Robinson (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1860-1900 (Box 145, Folder 1195)
    - Nail, John B. (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1860-1880 (Box 145, Folder 1196)
    - Nail, John E. (in Series IX, Photographs), undated (Box 145, Folder 1197)
    - Photograph album containing snapshots of Johnsons and Nails at Great Barrington, Massachusetts (in Series IX, Photographs), 1928-1930 (Box 146, Folder 1198)
    - Photograph of American Consulate in Venezuela (in Series IX, Photographs), 1910 (Box 146, Folder 1199)
    - Photograph of James Weldon Johnson High schools and YMCA (in Series IX, Photographs), circa 1960-1970 (Box 146, Folder 1200)
    - Photograph of Interior of Anne Spencer Garden House given to Okala by Chauncey and Anne Spencer (in Series IX, Photographs), 1985 (Box 146, Folder 1201)
    - Japanese prints (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1850-1900 (Box 147, Folder 1202-1209)
    - Painting of Man by Ragip (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), circa 1900 (Box 148, Folder 1210)
    - Painting of a Man by Muelfer (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), undated (Box 149, Folder 1211)
    - Plaque commemorating Johnson presented by the James Weldon Johnson Elementary School and illustrations of "The Creation" by students, New York City, New York (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1966 (Box 149, Folder 1212-1213)
    - Plaques awarding John B. Nail and John E. Nail life membership in the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1959, 1962 (Box 149, Folder 1214-1215)
    - Badge and cord for Negro Silent Protest Parade (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1917 (Box 150, Folder 1216-1217)
    - Metal plaque of Theodore Roosevelt presented to James Weldon Johnson (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), before 1938 (Box 151, Folder 1218)
    - International Postage Stamp Album belonging to John E. Nail (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1894 (Box 151, Folder 1219)
    - Example of box in which James Weldon Johnson and Grace Nail Johnson Papers originally housed at Beinecke Library (in Series X, Artwork and Objects), 1941 (Box 152, Folder 1220)
  - Record Album Storage
    - " God's Trombones Read by James Weldon Johnson and Selected 20th-Century Negro Poetry" (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), 1967 (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1221-1222)
    - "Lift Every Voice and Sing" performed by the Hampton Institute Choir (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), undated (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1223)
    - "The Black Scene in Prose, Poetry, and Song" read and sung by Vinie Burrows (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), 1961 (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1224)
    - "Conflict" recordings of poems by various artists (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), 1963 (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1225)
    - "The Gift of Song" music performed by the Collegiate Chorale of Philander Smith College (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), undated (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1226)
    - "Spoken English to Accompany the Roberts English Series," Third Book (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), circa 1961 (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1227)
    - "Simply Heavenly" (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), after 1957 (Box 153 (Record album storage), Folder 1228)
    - "The Harlem Renaissance and Beyond" (in Series XI, Audiovisual Material), 1969 (Box 154 (Record album storage), Folder 1229)
- Restricted Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Box 155 (Legal and financial records): Temporarily restricted. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Restricted Papers, 1968-1977 (Box 155, Folder 1230-1240)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Box 156: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 87, folders 681 and 689 (Box 156, Folder 1241)
  - Box 90, folders 721-723 (Box 156, Folder 1242)
  - Box 109, folder 956 (Box CS, Folder 1243)
  - Box 109, folders 967-969 (Box CS, Folder 1244)
  - Box 110, folder 970 (Box CS, Folder 1245)
  - Box 110, folder 971 (Box CS, Folder 1246)
  - Box 110, folder 972 (Box CS, Folder 1247)
  - Box 110, folder 974 (Box CS, Folder 1248)
  - Box 110, folders 975-977 (Box CS, Folder 1249)
  - Box 110, folders 982-985 (Box CS, Folder 1250)
  - Box 112, folders 1004-1012 (Box CS, Folder 1251)
  - Box 112, folder 1028 (Box CS, Folder 1252)